Kyle Langford

Senior Designer and Web Developer

HELLO!

With 10 years experience, I possess a strong blend of design talents and development experiences that can be used for a variety of digital projects. I am passionate about helping people use technology through design. I excel at problem-solving and visualizing client needs. I work well at managing expectations while communicating ideas and design strategies to teammates and clients.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr. Interactive Designer and Developer — Brunello, Inc.

6 Years, March 2012 - Current, 6 Employees, Boston MA

Designer and web developer specializing in UI/UX, front-end development and javascript applications. I have been working with Drupal for more than 7 years and have expert knowledge of web technologies and standards. I am involved with all aspects of web projects from planning and strategy, IA, UI/UX, to implementation and quality control. Frequently assist marketing efforts with email and social media integrations. Clients include Rodale, Linkwell Health, NonProfit Quaterly, Sasaki Associates, Dartmouth Alumni Magazine, Princeton Alumni Magazine.

Agency Partner — Raskyl Collective, Ilc.

7 Years, June 2011 - Current, 2 Employees, Boston MA

Local contracting and consulting team for the design and development of web-based solutions and marketing efforts, Projects range from design services, B2B tools, content managed websites, and email marketing. Past clients include GasBuddy, Drizly, Blueshift, Rate Gravity, Harvard Developmental Genome Project, MA/NH Emergency Nurses Association, WebGURU (NEU).

Lead Web Designer and Drupal Developer — Questex Media, Ilc.

2 Years, Nov 2010 - March 2012, 500+ Employees, Newton MA

Provided design services and Drupal site-building for internal publishing sites. Led our design team and worked with the project manager on meeting business initiatives and client goals. Sites used Drupal and covered a wide range of B2B industries.

Digital Producer — Northeastern University, Edtech Center

1 Year, January 2009 - May 2010, 12 Employees Boston MA

Instructed faculty members and graduate students on software and hardware solutions for their interactive media projects. Performed web-related production tasks and worked as part of the University's Second-life presence.

Environmental Designer — Wojciechowski Design

1 Year, Somerville MA, 4 Employees, July 2008 - April 2009

Worked as a project designer creating designs and production proofs for way-finding solutions that were used in libraries, museums, and schools. Primarily focused on designing an interior and exterior sign-system for the Cambridge Public Library. Produced 3D scale models in Sketch Up which were used to create stills and virtual walkthroughs.

203-803-6120 kyle.langford@gmail.com www.everhood.co Boston / Northshore, MA

EDUCATION

Northeastern University Boston, MA

Bachelor of Science Dual Major in Graphic Design and Multimedia, Minor in 3D Computer Animation.

DESIGN

UI, UX Design
RWD / Mobile First Design
Email Design
Information Architecture
Content Strategy
Sketch
Illustrator
Photoshop
Invision, Balsamiq
InDesign
After Effects
SketchUp, Blender

DEVELOPMENT

Solutions Planning
Technology Assessment
Rapid Prototyping
HTML1.0, HTML5, XML, JSON
CSS, SASS, SCSS, BEM
jQuery, underscore.js, backbone.js
Drupal 7 and 8
Angular 1.x
Node.js, NPM
Gulp.js, Grunt.js
Version Control, Git
Hosting, Acquia Cloud Hosting
API Intergrations
PHP, MYSQL

INTERESTS

Creating Cool Posters Design Process Skiing Woodworking